PABLO ARROYO NOE

Software development is not just coding, it can be a driving force for the technology that is changing the world for the better.

As an IT professional with more than 6 years of experience, I've understood that Best Practices are not enough to guarantee exceptional software. A well defined Architecture, predicting System Qualities, implementing Evolutionary Prototyping, and enhancing Stakeholder Communication are, among others, what sets apart functional software from industry game-changers.

SKILLS

SOFTWARE KNOWLEDGE

- · Design Patterns
- · Architectural Design
- · Backend Development
- · Frontend Development
- · APIs and Integrations
- · Database Design
- · Security

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · Version Control
- · Algorithms
- · Dev Ops
- · Optimization
- · Responsive Design
- · Scripting
- Testing

INDUSTRY KNOWLEDGE

- · Team Leadership
- · Digital Transformation
- · UI Design
- · UX Principles
- · Graphic Design
- · Digital Marketing

PROGRAMMING & MARKUP LANGUAGES

Ruby, JavaScript, Python C#, SQL, HTML, CSS

FRAMEWORKS, TOOLS & TECH

Ruby on Rails, GIT, AWS, Heroku React.Js, Docker, Kubernetes Linux, Sass, Node.js, WordPress

LANGUAGES

Spanish · Native English · Proficient

French · Reading & Writing

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Sustainability
Science
Trekking & Adventure
Traveling and Society
Culture

PABLONOE.COM

CARLOS ANTUNEZ 1875, APT 405 · SANTIAGO, CHILE (+56) 9 5257 0855 · PABLO.ARROYO.NOE@GMAIL.COM

EXPERIENCE

Great Place To Work® Chile SENIOR FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

March 2019 - Present

My work consists on designing and developing core business software solutions. These solutions, require scalable and available infrastructure, paired with highly modifiable and interoperable architecture, which has to take in consideration more than 8 stakeholders.

Responsible for supporting and guiding the development team by implementing good practices and establishing agile software methodologies, which allow the continual expansion and integration of our software assets, adding new functionality on a regular basis.

Being part of the Technology department, we provide our internal client with the proper tools, attending their needs and enabling digital transformation.

Viewnia.com

October 2017 - January 2020

TECHNICAL PROJECT LEAD

Viewnia.com is an innovative platform, that brings the Patagonian tourism to the world, in a modern format.

Viewnia's founders comisioned me with the development and deployment of a web application. With them and a team of designers, we conceptualized the first MVP. Approaching it's completion, I was not only working as a developer, but as a technical leader, providing technological knowledge and collaborating actively with the business.

Freelance

July 2014 - March 2019

SOFTWARE SOLUTIONS PROVIDER

As a freelance software solutions provider, I encountered a new world of knowledge and oportunity. This was, to date, my most complete and versatile work experience, since I had to simultaneously seek for jobs while designing, developing and executing projects. A demanding job of self discovery, fulfilling many roles and being responsible for the complete cycle of Software Projects, I was not only able to evaluate my interests and strengths, but also test my capacity and adaptability on several and diverse challenges.

Projects include complex web plaforms built with Ruby On Rails, e-commerce sites built with Shopify and Spree and websites built with React or vanilla HTML and CSS.

EDUCATION

Universidad Técnica Federico Santa María 2009 – 2014

INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING

Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile 2007 - 2008

AGRICULTURAL SCIENCES

Fundación Educacional Santiago College 1992 - 2006

INTERNATIONAL BACCALAUREATE ENGLISH SCHOOL

VOLUNTEERING

Fundación TECHO FIELD SUPERVISOR

2006 - 2014

Providing emergency housing for people across Chile and Paraguay, specially after the 2010 earthquake catastrophe. Collaborated as a squad member, truck driver, resource manager, recruiter and field operation supervisor, contributing with the creation of over 150 new homes and repairing of many others.

Date: 10 March 2020